Maybe you've been thinking, "This
journey has been interesting. It's been
useful. I'm picking up new skills, but I
wish it could go deeper, get more pro,
get more hardcore." Well, good news.
That's what we're doing. Welcome to week
two. Welcome to Pro week. And today is a
yellow day, which means it's a platform
day, a product day. And of all the
product days, this is the one. This is
the one that's near and dear to my
heart. This is Claude Code day. I'm
introducing claude code which is going
to be the the main point of focus for
the whole rest of the next two weeks but
we'll also look at open code and maybe
some others as well. So much to do
today. At the beginning of the course
last week I taken you through Steve
Yaggi's eight stages in the evolution of
AI coding starting with just using
chatbt and ending up all the way with
orchestration platforms like his own Gas
Town. And we talked about the that that
sort of evolution as the first four
being what we would do in week one.
Stage five is what we would really
hammer in week two now. And then six,
seven, and eight, the super fancy stuff
perhaps mostly in week three. And we
also went through the kinds of of the
three stages, the three types of coding
that were prevalent last year. uh which
was mostly what we did at the end of
last week about planning, executing,
reviewing and test, writing out your
spec, driving the process, and the trust
but verify mindset, which I think you'll
agree is very much what we had in our
project on day five of last week. And
these are the techniques that are
typically used for missionritical
software, for big code bases, and for
highly innovative code, which are using
sort of latest greatest libraries where
you have to work more carefully. But for
MVPs for new build where you have risk
appetite where you're just creating a
lot of boilerplate front-end codes say
which is which is ripe for automation
then you can be more bold you can go
with yolo you can have what's called
Ralph loops which we will explore this
week and you can even go to this kind of
multi- aent swarms orchestration stuff
that we'll focus on next week. So this
just gives you again the kind of lay of
the land and I need to press home on the
point that was emphasized in the
jellyfin post if you remember that that
it is your job and my job to deliver
code that that we are accountable for
that we have proven to ourselves that it
works and it's good. We can use LLMs to
help us. We can use them to expand our
capabilities to use Andre's word. But
the the key is that we are responsible
for the quality of the code we deliver
and for making sure that it works. Now,
if last week was about vibe coding, vibe
coding for fun and profit. This week is
changing the conversation to be about
something called vibe engineering. And
that's not necessarily a proper phrase.
It was a it was a term that was coined
by Simon Willis, amazing AI engineer and
writer who I will often often show you
his stuff. uh but he made this this uh
blog post which I will show you uh and
he says I feel like vibe coding pretty
well established as covering the fast
loose irresponsible way of building with
AI prompt driven no attention to how the
code actually works and so this leaves
us with with what he calls a terminology
gap a missing word what do we call the
other end of the spectrum where seasoned
professionals accelerate their work with
LLMs whilst proudly and confidently
staying accountable for the software
they produce and he proposes we call it
vibe engineering and your tongue
slightly and cheek but not really. He
really really wants this term and and I
see why and it is taking off somewhat
and certainly it's in the spirit of this
exact write up here that we're going to
go through our material this week. It's
somewhat consistent with day five of
last week but just taking it further.
It's about being highly productive,
highly effective and impactful, uh, but
whilst keeping accountability for the
code you build, doing it in a
bulletproof way. That is vibe
engineering. And so, in fact, we will
take a second to go through his post
just so I can show you some of the
points he makes because it's so well
done. This is this is his blog and it's
an amazing blog. We've already gone
through the first section. Let me keep
going. One of the lesser spoken truths
of working with LM is that it's
difficult. There's a lot of depth to
understanding the tools. There are traps
and the pace at which they can turn out
code. It it's uh it can be crazy. The
rise of coding agents like Claude code
first released in February. Uh Codeex
CLI, the CLI version, and Gemini CLI,
the CLI version. We've been using the
IDE versions of these can iterate on
code, test and modify until it achieves
a goal. It's dramatically increased the
usefulness of LLMs as we will see when
we use the CLI tools this week. And then
he says, I'm increasingly hearing from
experienced, credible engineers who are
running multiple agents at once,
tackling several projects in problems in
parallel and expanding the scope of what
they can do. He was skeptical to start
with, but now he's doing it himself, and
it's effective, if mentally exhausting.
And that's more what we'll be doing next
week. It feels different from classic
vibe coding. Most uh he built lots of
tools that way and his tools are
amazing. Uh but iterating with with
coding agents to produce production
quality code feels like a different
process entirely. And it's also clear
that they reward top processes.
Automated testing. Building a testing
process in planning in advance. We've
done a fair amount of that with like the
plan that we did on day five and then
executing it step by step. comprehensive
documentation. We've been doing that.
We've been seeing how that works. Good
version control habits. We've been
taking git checkpoints, but we'll be
doing more this week with checkpointing
built into Claude Code and highly
effective automation. So, we'll
certainly be doing plenty of that this
week. And now, Simon makes some real pro
points. I just love to share with you.
Uh, a culture of code review, making
sure that your LLM reviews its own work.
We've done that already a couple of
times. so powerful. A very weird form of
management. Getting good results feels
uncomfortably close to getting good
results out of a human collaborator, but
with some differences that he points
out. Really good manual QA, being able
to do that, as well as the automated
sort. Strong research skills,
understanding there's many different
ways that you can ask for a problem, and
sometimes you hit a blocker, it's good
just to step back and just try again
with a different way of doing it. and
having that mindset, which is hard
because you want to solve the problem
you've got and knowing when to just try
something different. It's it's a real
skill. The ability to to ship a preview
is a very interesting point. Um, an
instinct for what you can outsource to
an AI and what you cannot. This I I just
couldn't agree more with Simon. It's
such a key point. I've developed over
time this good sense of the fact that,
for example, front end is something that
I can absolutely just delegate to the
LLM. It will build a front end. and I
can give it some feedback, it's going to
be great. When it comes to backend and
particularly say working actually with
LLMs, it's often struggling. And for
example, in week one, day five, we I
came back and looked at that main Python
module and whilst it was working, it was
a mess and it had a bunch of things in
it which were were needed to be
refactored. and and that's why you need
to have a really good instinct for what
are the LLMs reliable at doing and what
are they not and being able to jump in
and help there. And an interesting point
is that the way we estimate projects has
changed. It's always been hard for a
software engineer and now in some ways
it's easier, in some ways it's harder.
Often these tools like Claude Code will
be able to rattle out code really,
really quickly and you get this false
sense that you can accomplish incredible
things in minutes, but then you hit a
wall and then you could be stuck for
several hours bashing your head against
a wall on something that feels like it
should be really easy. Uh, and so you
need to factor that into your estimates.
As I say, you know, don't don't get
caught up in the hype of the 10X.
There's a huge efficiency improvement
here. And and to Andre's point, you can
expand your capabilities, but there are
definitely drawbacks and you need to
factor them in. And and all of this is
kind of summarized here by Simon. He
says if you're going to really exploit
these capabilities, you need to be at
the top of your game. Uh the designing
success criteria, remember that we've
done that many times. designing agentic
loops, planning QA, managing a growing
army of weird digital interns who will
absolutely cheat if you give them a
chance, and spending so much time on
code review. Very wise words. Read this
whole blog post, link in the resources.
This is gold.